BRETT WHITESIDE

Mount Morris, MI · 817-713-6074

Brettwhiteside4@gmail.com ·https://www.linkedin.com/in/brett-e-whiteside/

I spent the first 10 years professionally working in the aerospace industry where I quickly rose from an entry level position to roles involving greater detail/precision, the last 5 years of my time in the industry I worked in Quality Assurance as a CMM Programmer/Quality Inspector. I am highly detail-oriented making QA a perfect department for someone such as myself, and was time and time again very beneficial for myself as well as my past employers. I have a real knack for catching mistakes be them errors on certifications, missed dimensions in reports prepared for customers, flaws/discrepancies pertaining to prints/designs, incorrect identification, etc. In addition to CMM programming I was also in charge of maintaining the calibrated equipment for the companies I worked for, the calibration log, & determining intervals for calibration of said equipment. Other duties included performing hand checks (calipers, micrometer, height gage, indicators, etc.), composing the TIRs (tooling inspection record), putting together the packages of deliverable documentation for customers, performing proof loads, providing photographs of tooling for customers, etc. I have been in leadership roles both in High School (as a peer assistance leader), as well as professionally (as a manager) and taking the lead on aerospace projects within my former companies. With regard to the aerospace industry, I have experience with Verisurf, CATIA, QUINDOS & PC-DMIS software.

At the start of 2021, I became interested in the world of web development/coding and am currently wrapping up a Full-Stack Web Development bootcamp before continuing my college education part time in pursuit of a bachelors in Computing and Information Technologies. My background in Quality Assurance has already benefited me greatly in my studies and will translate well to my future employment as I transition out of the aerospace industry.

EXPERIENCE

2007-2012

MANAGER, PIZZA PRO

I was the manager for a local pizza restaurant in Texas as I finished High School and started college.

2012 - 2021

CMM PROGRAMMER/QUALITY INSPECTOR, MODELS & TOOLS

I started out at the bottom of the totem pole with the aforementioned aerospace company, worked my way up quite quickly, learning how to laser track along the way, and for the last 4+ years I was in the Quality Assurance department. During my time in QA the company won numerous awards and accolades, most notably Elite Supplier Awards from Lockheed Martin for 3 years in a row. This award is only given out to the top 1% of Lockheed's 10,000+ global suppliers.

2021 - 2022

SENIOR CMM PROGRAMMER, JENOPTIK AUTOMOTIVE NORTH AMERICA

I was in charge of the entire CMM lab during my time with Jenoptik. I conducted inspection on all in house parts and masters, as well as inspected parts/masters for our customers. In addition to

physically setting and running the parts/masters, I was also responsible for writing the actual programs (using QUINDOS) to do so, and creating the certificates thereafter. I took part in weekly status meetings to help plan projects around the capabilities and timing of the lab/CMM.

Drawing on my quality background I helped restructure the system in which all results, certifications, designs, customer communication, internal communication, etc. were stored as well as kept the lab equipment calibrated to industry lab standards. I also worked to revamp certain aspects of the QMS (Quality Management System) and helped lead the company to a successful ISO/IEC 17025 audit performed by A2LA.

While I enjoyed my time at Jenoptik, I ultimately left the company in August of 2022 to focus on completing my web development bootcamp I was and am currently enrolled in & to focus on a career change more thoroughly.

EDUCATION

AUGUST 2005-JUNE 2009

HIGH SCHOOL, AZLE HIGH SCHOOL

I graduated with a GPA in the mid 90's, was a part of a peer assistance program (PALs), and was in advanced placement courses my entire 4 years.

AUGUST 2009-JUNE 2011

DID NOT FINISH, WEST TEXAS A&M

I continued school following my first year at Texas A&M at a local community college before being offered a position at an aerospace company (Models & Tools) after 2 years of college.

JULY 2021-CURRENT

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP, CAREER FOUNDRY

I began taking this course part time as I continued to work in the aerospace industry and as it stands, I will have completed the course by mid-December 2022.

SKILLS

- Very detail oriented, I've found a way to channel my OCD tendencies into a positive attribute professionally.
- HTML5 (1 year experience)
- CSS (1 year experience)
- JavaScript (1 year experience)
- Server-Side & Client-Side Programming (1 year experience)
- React (6 months experience)
- React Native (6 months experience)
- Bootstrap (1 year experience)

- Git (1 year experience)
- GitHub (1 year experience)
- Node.js (1 year experience)
- MongoDB (1 year experience)
- Rest APIs (1 year experience)
- Unit/Integration/End-to-End Testing & User Acceptance (6 months experience)
- PWAs (6 months experience)
- JSON (1 year experience)
- TypeScript/Angular (minimal experience)
- Postman (6 months experience)

- Not afraid to take the lead or be a dependable asset to accomplish a task.
- I love a challenge, and am passionate about/get joy from solving problems.
- Used to working with people of different ages/walks of life.
- Strong desire to continue learning any skills to benefit myself future employers

ACTIVITIES

I am passionate about puzzles, music, podcasts, comedy, traveling, exercising, etc.